<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Monica Chan</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/post/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Monica Chan</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>About me!</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/images/alchemist.png" alt="Featured image of post About me!" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hi there! I&amp;rsquo;m Monica Chan, a senior studying EECS at MIT.
My interests include embedded systems, software design and integration, digital design, and AI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am on track to graduate with my Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s in EECS from MIT in 2025, and a Master&amp;rsquo;s in EECS from MIT in 2026.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve worked at Renesas Electronics, Tesla, SpaceX, Palantir, and I will be working at Waymo starting in 2026. At Renesas I was responsible for delivering a lossy inductor model for simulation in Simplis. At Tesla, I developed the Service UI Charging Panel for Cybertruck, created fleet analysis tools for Service Engineering, and contributed to Service Engineering for Cybertruck launch. At SpaceX, I was on the ground segment telemetry team for Falcon, providing automation tools for operators on console and installing weather stations in Cape Canaveral. At Palantir, I was a Forward Deployed Software Intern in the NYC office working on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mBDQK7OJ1Ls&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;racecar workflows&lt;/a&gt; for Andretti Indycar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be working full time at Waymo as a Product Manager on the Perception team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can email me at mochan (at) mit (dot) edu&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Because Racecar</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/post/blog/because-racecar/because_racecar/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/blog/because-racecar/because_racecar/</guid>
        <description></description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
